AA sigidi of
[Applause]
Microsoft thank you very much this has
this has to be the uh nicest
introduction I got ever and I'm sure it
made me
blush um and uh yeah so uh welcome
everybody to the uh talk about uh real
time tweet delivery architecture at
Twitter you were supposed to have Rafi
standing here Rafi is an ex- colleague
of mine he is director of platform
services at Twitter and
uh he's unfortunately unable to be here
but he is here uh with us on Skype say
hello
Rafi hello everybody I'm sorry I
couldn't make it in person right
excellent but he'll be here he is
probably better qualified to uh answer
the questions and uh and uh he is uh
he's of course free to chime in anytime
I uh leave something out or or maybe get
something wrong the reason I uh am
standing here in front of you is um I'm
currently with uh well Oracle instead of
Microsoft and uh I'm here at the
Stockholm office so I was at hand as a
substitution so uh uh I did actually
work uh for Twitter before for for about
two years before I joined oraca and I
was working in a in a runtime systems
team that's closely working that's
closely working with rafi's team and uh
so uh as luck has it I did actually work
on uh mostly Performance Tuning some of
those services that we will be talking
about making sure that they're not just
nominally real time but like really real
time so with that uh let's get into
it rafy has all the nicest transitions
in
slides so uh yeah I am channeling him
today um so if I haven't told you that I
work for Oracle you would get a clue
this is the standard disclaimer even if
this guy lies through his teeth uh we
don't care don't hold it against
us so uh all right uh we will talk
mostly about uh timeline delivery when
talk about tweet delivery it is really
all about uh about timelines timelines
are chronologically reversed ordered
series of tweets um
and uh that everybody who uses Twitter
No Doubt uh knows how does that look
like uh there are several categories of
these uh we have uh soal targeted
timelines your home timeline is typical
targeted timeline when you log on to
Twitter what you see is your home
timeline it's targeted it's personalized
for you uh there is a we can we can get
them as as as pull timeline so when you
log on to Twitter what you get your your
browser is pulling the timeline down um
or any of the Twitter clients hit
twitter.com you will be uh interacting
with the home timeline API and you will
be pulling your current timeline from
there uh aside from this there is a
queried timeline when you are doing a
real-time request into Twitter and you
are asking it to search in the in the in
the overall Corpus of the tweets based
on keywords then you are doing a uh
I what you get you're getting a query
timeline you're using the search API uh
when you hit this API with particular
parameters you're causing a search
process to go through the system we'll
get to
that and aside from the pool based uh
tweet delivery uh we also have uh
varieties of push based deliveries and
there is a equival there is a duality to
Target it and quered on the push side
one of those
uh are the user and the S streams we
will cover what exactly do these mean
later and uh with those we can can we
can deliver uh timelines to your device
uh without the device having to pull
having to pull all the time uh normally
through an open uh socket um the uh one
of those said user side streams the
other kind is the so-called uh uh track
follow which is sort of like a stand
ending search query uh you open a
connection to this API you
specify certain set of users or or
tokens that you're interested in and
those tweets that come in the real time
they match these uh they match these uh
the criteria that you set they get
pushed to your
device
um all right so um how does this
typically look like well uh let's let's
talk about uh
uh a bit of a quick overview of how does
Twitter work people tweet when they do
they are filling their so-called user
timeline this is a snippet of my user
timeline that rafre three few days ago
and it's particularly funny and uh um so
these are some of my tweets as they were
happening now if somebody's following
myself and maybe Matias then you have
another set of tweets that Matias was
tweeting and if the somebody is also
following J Focus then you will have
another set of tweets that the J Focus
account is tweeting now normally if you
follow these three people what you get
is
a reverse time ordered merge of uh of
all the tweets of the people you follow
now of course this is not that trivially
easy because um the timeline rules are a
little bit more complicated we have at
replies um we have um retweets and there
are rules for when do you see a retweet
you might see a tweet from somebody you
don't follow because somebody who you
follow did retweet their tweet uh if
people are having a threaded
conversation using at replies at each
other you only see those if you follow
both part to the conversation otherwise
if uh if I respond to a tweet from
someone and uh there is somebody
observing me as I'm tweeting he follows
me but he doesn't follow the person that
I had replied to he won't see that part
of the
conversation these are uh tried and
tested rules over the years uh and uh
and of course they have to manifest
themselves in the software so
compositing a merged timeline is not all
that trivial so obviously we cannot
really do it all the time on every
request because it would be horribly
slow um several years ago when I was was
actually joining Twitter I uh I have a
friend and my friend uh asked me so how
many people work at Twitter and that
time it was 300 I think right now it's
probably more like 1500 people something
like that but my friend was actually
uh was actually completely incredulous
when he heard the 300 he was like three
what could possibly 300 people do there
this is such an easy service I could
write this in an afternoon and yeah of
course you could and it would work for
you and five for
friends so anyway let's see how this
works uh you tweet
something this tweet will hit the
so-called right API it's an HTTP
endpoint we are of course highly
abstracting the system here and what
happens is that once we hit the right
API we need need to ensure that all of
your followers will see this tweet
hopefully in something that can be
considered real
time uh what we don't show is that the
Tweet will first uh be written to dis
and a quick HTTP response uh uh will be
returned to the client so everything is
asynchronous decoupled from there on we
don't want people to have to keep
persistent connection what when they
tweet we want them we want to return to
them a quick HTTP 200 okay as soon as
possible because maybe they tweeting
from a mobile device that wouldn't be
too good at maintaining a longer
connection and so on so try to be nice
and quick we want to return within 50
milliseconds after we we eliminated
duplicate tweets because we watch for
that and other like trivial business
logic in the in the in the Tweet format
of the HTP request so what happens after
that is what we call a fan out we call
it fan out because we take every
incoming tweet and insert it into the
home timelines of all the the people who
are following the author of that tweet
we fan it out into all into all the home
timelines where they need to
go we have a timeline cache and this
timeline cache is based on redis reddis
is a very nice uh inmemory key Value
Store um it's sort of like mcash except
that uh it it allows for uh mcash deals
in binary blobs uh redis deals in
structured data and this is actually
significant for us
um
the but anyway you can think of it as an
inmemory key Value Store uh now of
course we don't have a single reddis
instance we have a huge Bank of redice
instances that are uh keeping the uh uh
timeline cache and in addition to that
for fault tolerance every person's
timeline will not live on a single
instance it lives at three instances so
when it has to be retrieved if the the
first machine that you hit for a
particular timeline based on some kind
of a um hashing algorithm obviously you
uh don't find it there you can go around
find it in in a second or third instance
hopefully um at a at Twitter scale
machines just fall over every time you
have to plan for that it it's just part
of the business you never have an
assumption that something is up if you
do your system won't be terribly
stable so uh what Fen out does is we
have the social graph service which uh
maintains the information of who follows
who among other things and uh figures
out all the people who are following the
author of the tweet and then start uh
the insert process into reddest
instances
um Fen out itself is not just a single
machine obviously that's also a bank of
machines and they're interconnected many
to many with all the Rices there's a lot
of TCP connections being open at the
same time uh but that's the way it it it
has to be so say rafy tweets or I tweet
and then we carry redis for uh okay who
are the people who follow Rafi and then
we have to append this tweet into each
of their timelines now insert into
reddis uh for every users's home
timeline there is a there is
a well there is a there is a key in the
Redd is key of the recipient and uh we
will just append to that it's replicated
and U also we are pipelining to about 4K
destinations at the time so we are
chunking it into 4,000 followers uh push
this to Red at
once
um using redice
is nice and why do I oh so
just sorry I'm having a my machine is
having a senior
moment all right um so as I said we have
a native list structure in reddis so we
can just append one after the other uh
back in the day in the ancient history
probably four years ago um I think for a
while we tried using mcash for uh for
these and of course it didn't work out
after a while because every time you had
to pull in from the mcash the binary
blob that was the timeline app pendant
element to it then serialize the whole
thing back with redis we just tell it
here's this key push this element to the
listen redis actually knows about data
structures band with wide uh band with
wise it's it's just so much nicer uh we
use the r push X command which uh
basically in red this means if the key
is not there ignore this command so we
are not doing any work for uh for uh
those people whose time timelines are
not cached and whose people's timelines
are not cached well people who are
inactive so if you haven't logged into
Twitter for a long time your timeline
will eventually fall out from the cach
because reddis is an inmemory uh thing
if uh you assign it um you know 24 gigs
of memory on that particular box then uh
whenever it has to uh uh to uh you you
can configure it with a policy that
whenever uh it uh needs to uh needs to
uh evacuate something from memory
because it's just running at full
capacity or just be throwing away the
oldest item so it it works as an lru
cache so uh what we store normally is ID
of the Tweet the user ID and some
additional bits we are not storing the
whole tweet because that would be hugely
redundant because as same tweet if I
tweet something to my meager 2.5k
followers then uh you will have to uh
have that stored 2,500 times if Lady
Gaga tweets something then honestly I
have I don't even have an idea how many
followers she has these days
um it's either single digit millions or
double digit Millions one of the two um
so obviously we don't want to replicate
a lot of that
um so uh the other thing we do is redis
is really good at storing variable
length entries so there's no need for
all of these records to actually be the
same length I mean r this is beautiful I
just cannot say enough nice things about
it we really love it so uh in case that
your Tweet is actually not a tweet but a
retweet we can we can we can append the
uh the ID of the original tweet to uh to
your retweet when you retweet something
you actually gener behind the scenes
you're generating a new tweet with its
own ID but it's linked to whatever was
the retweeted
one uh as I said we are highly redundant
within data center if you wonder about
the cross data center replication
then uh we are not doing it on the
redest level there's just too much
bandwidth there there's too much uh
traffic that would be going on we
actually do the replication on the right
API level so the the the Tweet stream as
it comes in the right API is actually
replicated to additional data centers
and all the computation is basically
repeated in every data center that's
what uh worked best uh for
Twitter so after after a while you want
to pull this thing in your browser what
happens is that there exist a thing
called D timeline service which will
read these red Rices or red
eye um so uh TW is obviously more than
an ID in order to get this nice display
you need to compose it from user the
user's icon the text of the Tweet uh
geoinformation whether you favored this
tweet already or not uh
that all needs to be in the rendered
version of the tweet this is the So-Cal
hydrated tweet and the timeline Services
is interacting with other services to uh
to to to hydrate tweet from the Tweet ID
that it pulled from
redis um
however uh the uh the thing is if you
are in cash this process takes about 50
milliseconds it's nicely optimized over
the years if you are out of the cash
then what timeline service has to do so
you haven't logged in for Twitter for
several weeks you fell out of the cache
uh we started updating your timeline
with tweets as they come in in redis um
then this timeline service will have to
hit the social graph service figure out
who you follow query their timelines
reassemble your home timeline stick it
into reddis and then carry on and uh
that takes about 3 seconds but it only
happens for uh for uh uh people that uh
that were inactive for for a
time so this was the um the uh basic
targeted timeline in a pool mode Let's
talk about search a little bit um search
works sometime somewhat different the
right API also Forks off to a thing
named
ingester which
uh uh which goes to um which tokenizes
the tweet and then we have a search
index which runs on a bunch of services
named the early bird at Twitter
everything has to be a bird uh uh early
bird is actually an optimiz think of
think of it as an optimized Lu scine it
mostly is an optimized Lu scine uh of
course we have a bunch of those again
however the the significant difference
is that uh uh
while the insert into the redice fans
out so it's potentially an order and
operation based on how many followers
you have this guy here in Jester it
tokenizes the tweet and uses the tokens
plus other signal GE information and so
on and just pushes it into the relevant
index for for uh uh in in in the search
index in in a particular uh early bird
and then when you do a search you are
faced with a thing called blender which
is a quite ingenious uh uh piece of
engineering uh that some really really
smart folks in the search organization
did and uh it does a really nice uh and
quick scatter GA of or early birds for
the index for all the terms in the
search query that you did applies some
more signals from your search it might
uh figure out who you are where you are
what were your past interests and so on
based on that ranks the results and then
does a real time merge and presents all
of that to you as far as we are
concerned though the the delivery self
from right
API until the index it happens really
quickly because we are just inserting
into index per token there's no fan out
as such so you see there's this
interesting counter balance redis uh
timeline caching is a little bit it's
it's expensive on the write it's cheap
on the read search is cheap on the Cheap
on the right more expensive on the read
fortunately we have a lot more of those
than we have of uh of
those all
right oh yeah uh in aside from explicit
queries we also have a kind of an
implicit query which is the Discover tab
discover tab is basically an implicit
query it also runs off of blender as I
said it you you're logged in right so
there is probably an information about
your geolocation your past interest and
so on so this is it is also used blender
is also used uh to compose the the
discovered tab that's on the far left
right
now all right um that's the pool mode
this was the search API let's look into
push many nice transitions here yep
repeat all right the push
cluster obviously uh we have uh HTTP
push and mobile push let's discuss HTTP
push first um the
this is if if you could like real time
look at the bandwidth that comes in
Twitter you would see something
something crazy like this is a bit like
the Matrix isn't it uh this is uh Json
ised tweets a tweet might be 140
characters but when you uh tokenize it
extract the entities the URLs the the
usernames whatnot they usually can get
up to few kilobytes of Json and this is
normally the internal form that they are
being trafficked within the Twitter
system
um we have a service that's called hose
bird and this maintains persistent
connections with the end clients um it
is mostly an a routing cluster right now
for all public tweets you need about 25
megabytes per second bandwidth to to
consume all the public tweets and
uh and uh not just tweets but also the
events I have to emphasize the events
because you'll see why they're
interesting why they're important
uh so the right API can also hit the
hose bird now hose bird is um it just
gets all the tweets and then it routes
them into different cues for public
tweets for for social events like people
follow unfollow delete tweets these are
all additional events that need to be uh
taken into account they need to be paid
attention to in order to have everything
consistent and work
correctly um as SLA is about 150
milliseconds and sending these out and
we need to figure out what to do now the
thing is obviously you cannot have a
single machine for that uh at any given
time we have about 1 million clients
connecting to the push API that's 1
million open sockets no way there
there's no Hardware right now on planet
that handles this for single machine and
even if it did it would be really really
bad for failover wouldn't it so uh uh so
what there is is there is a there's a I
mean I mean structurally is beautiful
right that it's a cascading cluster you
have one machine everything comes in it
fans it out to two or several other
machines the next level which mostly do
nothing but fend them out to another
level and another level and there is
four levels of cascading in the hosb
cluster right now and you can always add
a fifth one if people start tweeting
five as much as they do these days um
and that last level is mostly that
maintains the it's the edge it maintains
connection with the external clients
with the Tweet decks and twitters for
mac and any other third- party clients
uh of this
world uh they are running on uh on on
gigabit Ethernet cards and they are
provisioned for about between two and
the three times of the highest observed
Spike so far so you know there there
there is some addition there is some
additional capacity in the system there
has to be uh an interesting tidbit
social graph
changes happen 10 times more often than
actual tweets you wouldn't think this is
true but I mean when I when I learned
that I was I was flabbergasted too but
uh uh in the in the in the host bird
events stream the social graph changes
actually are 10x to
tweets it's quite
amazing so
um what kind of clients do we have on
the other hand well we have the fire
hose which is you have an edge machine
it's just this basically raw input of
public tweets it goes out to it this is
not publicly available uh companies pay
for this Google used to pay for it so
that it could real time index it other
companies are paying for it uh of course
uh it's also not publicly available
because it's quite costly to maintain
you need to provide a 25 megabyte per
second connection to that entity that's
purchasing this from you um for and and
of course you can only just have a
limited number of these per box because
it's it's really it's like a huge
bandwidth that's why it's called fire
hose we used to also have a garden hose
I don't know whether that exists anymore
where you could uh uh without paying you
could subscribe to a fraction 1% or
something like that of the public tweets
if you wanted to sample them for
research I'm not sure whether that
exists anymore rafy do you
know yeah we still do support it for
smaller organizations mhm all
right okay so this is fireh house you
have the other thing which is the So-Cal
track follow track follow is if you ever
use the um tweet deck then uh in tweet
deck you can uh specify I want to see
all the tweets from this user and that
user and another user and additionally
all the tweets that mention J Focus or
Stockholm and then and then you will get
a real time push of those what happens
is that the the tweets are tokenized the
edge machine when you open the
connection to this you're actually
sending an HTTP request that has a huge
list of parameters saying these are all
the tokens I'm interested in and then
it's doing the filtering and only
sending you those tokens that that that
uh you are interested in this is a this
is search light in a sense that uh
instead of hitting the expensive blender
query API you are just getting a uh uh
stream that's filtered on user and
content tokens uh we might be sending
you a little bit more than you
originally wanted to get but this is
counteracted by the fact that the the
client tweet deck or whoever can do some
client side filtering on it additionally
so we don't worry much about
that um and there is the user streams
which basically replicates your home
timeline experience you log into the uh
Twitter for Mac or Twitter on your
iPhone and as tweets or tweetbot or
whatever and as tweets are coming in you
are just
getting them right so it's almost
identical to track follow except that
instead of you specifying the Search
terms it's basically saying anything
tweeted by these
people you will send it out on the
socket so anything tweeted out by your
followers it will be sent out of the uh
through through this socket and the
reason why we have to propagate social
graph changes through this cluster as
well is that if you start to follow
somebody new then all the edge machine
machines will have to get notified that
hey this guy is now following somebody
new so yeah now you will need to stream
additional tweets through that
connection for that for that person for
his Mac on
iPad uh or you stop stop following
somebody or you blocked somebody then
obviously again this needs to be updated
uh most of the uh most of the RAM and
CPU in these machines is actually uh
used by maintaining this kind of a cach
coherence uh of
course I think we also do something
since we have a lot of these machines
they will do rolling uh updates uh of
social graph as well so sometime they
just throw away whatever is CED and
refresh from the social graph just for
additional
consistency all right so
um this is what we covered so far which
is quite a lot so there is your Twitter
for Mac basically when this thing uh
runs it it never hits the pool API it
just goes through push except when you
start it because when you start it uh if
it only used the push API your Twitter
client would start blank and as people
are real- time tweeting you it will
start to fill up but that's bad user
experience you would like to see the
tweets uh that were tweeted several
minutes before you launched your client
so in launch Twitter from Mac or IP
iPhone iPad whatever it goes to the
timeline service pulls tweets back fills
its UI and after that it only talks to
the HTTP push well except if you scroll
back a lot then it again has to talk to
the timeline service but mostly we try
to avoid
it all right we covered almost all of
push except the mobile push so um yeah
let's quickly talk about
that mobile push
is very it's somewhat similar to http
push and it's somewhat similar to The
reddis Fan out it's an interesting
hybrid of the two um every tweet will
hit the mobile push demons which are
similar to The a little bit similar to
how fan out works because the mobile
push demos will also interrogate the
social service graph to figure out who
do you mobile follow now um Twitter
actually has more than one follower
graph because there is such a thing as
follow and there is such thing as mobile
follow you might be following a lot of
people but you don't necessarily want to
um be notified when all in SMS when all
of those people uh tweet so you can
separately specify who are people for
whom you might want to get uh push push
notifications on iPhone or SMS and so on
so uh it interrogates for the mobile
follow and and to all your mobile
followers then it similarly fans out
except instead of into a timeline
cache this works in a separate data
center which has dedicated lines for
almost all of the world's mobile phone
carriers it's a when you think about it
it's quite scary right but this is what
it does and then you know just exerts
pressure on them just sends to their API
saying uh we have a phone number of on
file send this SMS to this phone number
and pushes there's usually a bit of a
back pressure on that so uh when your
tweets get dropped it's most likely not
Twitter more likely AT&T but let's not
shift the blame but anyway yes let's
shift the blame it's
them and yeah that's pretty much how it
works all right
um so the idea is that we actually want
to um ideally we would like to all
computation to happen within 100 seconds
of a tweet arriving within
Twitter I'm not sure whether we are
whether we are hitting the goal yet or
not but most of the computation should
actually happen obviously you have I
mean a big fan out to Red this will will
will will take a
while all
right what else do we have okay this is
a recap slide oh yeah we have batch
computation um this is not real time
it's included for the sake of
completeness uh there is a honking big
Bank of clusters which also receive all
the right API run a bunch load of
analytics on it and if you don't log
into a Twitter for a day or so you might
actually receive an email from Twitter
saying hey these are some tweet that we
think are interesting and that you might
have
missed that's what Hado does uh runs
analytics and uh sends you out this
email it again it knows what you might
you might find interesting only from
people you follow but then it can use a
bunch of signals as in what was
interesting to you in the past what
tweets with links from those have people
clicked the most that's why it's good to
have a routing URL shortener for better
or worse um and that's what the hudo
cluster does this is not real time it
runs uh nightly right now I think uh
whenever they can they will try to make
it uh uh hourly or even more frequent
obviously the more frequent the better
the better it can service everybody
right I think it runs nightly so when we
talk about the path we have the
synchronous path which is hitting the
right API as I said aside
from a little bit of tweet D duplication
and similar it returns really quickly
within five 50 milliseconds or less so
as to not confuse your device trying to
go over a shaky Edge
connection and uh everything after that
happens completely asynchronously
completely independent this three pass
uh happen uh completely independent of
each other and this is the Tweet
delivery and uh there is the and there
obviously there's a query path for when
you go to the website you query the
timeline and you have the discovery and
the search there just a quick recap so
RAF You' like to us to talk about some
things we're trying namely uh again you
tweet something and it hits the right
API goes to the ingestor goes to early
bids and Rices uh
one of these things is fairly much like
the other right so one side is ingesting
into surged indexes so the Tweet will be
indexed into the index for the word
hello and the index for the for the word
world and on the fan out if we go to the
fan out index roughy tweets then we know
that Dana is following him so we'll need
to insert the Tweet into Dana's index so
it's all about inserting tweet IDs into
indexes they're really really similar
right so we always have a user intent
you have a query expansion which uh uh
when you search for Hello World you want
to search for the intersection of the
indexes hello and the world on the other
hand when you say I want raf's home
timeline which is now right now works
from redis what you're really saying is
you want this key from the reddis but
this key from the red this is actually a
union of a bunch of others because if
Rafi follows Nelson and Dana then uh
then we will need to uh actually get a
get a merge of these people's uh
people's indices so both of these things
are Boolean operations on indices they
are very
similar so there are some thinking on U
how the hell could we unify these things
right so uh but you also see there's
this interesting Duality one is Fan in
one is fan out the other is fan out one
is cheap to write expensive to read one
is expensive to write cheap to read and
it works right now because people search
less than they update their timeline so
you would think it's fine except for one
little
thing
celebrities uh when celebrities tweet
then you might have to update like few
Millions timelines that takes time it
introduces unpredictability into the
system and uh and you know uh uh good
system engineer gets nervous when
there's unpredictability so you are it's
hard to capacity plan for that so you
would like to do uh you you would like
lesson city in in your
system and so how well one thing that
can be done is
uh okay 10 minutes excellent all right
that chimes in with my own timer and uh
so uh you could do things where you we
say okay if somebody has a lot of follow
followers so we have a celebrity
threshold Twitter celebrity threshold
that' be a nice thing right like 2
million followers you have more than two
million followers then uh Twitter will
just not fan out your tweets into
redis just not instead when somebody
wants to pull their timeline and they
are following some celebrities then what
we do we return the ruffy's home
timeline so rfy needs his timeline we
return timeline into which we were
merging all the uh the uh less followed
people so myself my tweets would end up
uh in that particular index uh because I
don't have many followers but uh roughy
likes Taylor Swift apparently so uh uh
and when she tweets uh we wouldn't merge
Taylor's uh tweets into roughest
timeline rather when Rafi retrieves the
timeline we would do a real-time merge
of celebrities so we have a pre-computed
preached partial
timeline for for lighter uh lightly
followed people and we have a real-time
merge of Highly followed people so
writing gets cheaper reading gets a bit
more expensive depends on where you make
your threshold you can you can hit a
sweet spot with a computation so that's
one of the things that might be thought
of as experiment there's also the
question of a streaming compute uh this
is the generalization of the push
infrastructure hose bird is a pretty old
piece of uh Twitter infrastructure but
it's not leveraged for any other
purposes except for this kind of a light
tokenization delivery and track and
follow and so on uh there is uh Nathan
matz has his Cloud uh sorry storm it's
hard to get up to date with all the
weather-based
terminology uh so he has a storm uh
computational uh continuous
computational system written inclosure
it's actually a really really nice piece
of code um it's it's available on GitHub
and Twitter is U internally I guess
starting to deliver it for things you
can do things like a realtime
clickstream analysis for figuring out
people's interests so that in a real
time you can re rerank search results
because you can quickly notice that
something became more uh popular than
something else it can be uh used for a
lot of things this is basically a
generalization of the push mechanism you
want to do more computation on the right
PA and uh end up with hopefully less dis
and memory usage on the read
pass
so so these are some of the things that
we're trying uh okay recap of the uh
full system and uh we'll finish with uh
some timeline
statistics Twitter has about 150 million
active users worldwide you get about
300,000
uh uh pole base bed timeline requests
per second that's quite a lot um the 8
percen for the for satisfying this
lookup is 1 millisecond that's amazing
uh four uh 99% is four milliseconds
typically 1 millisecond is for the
redest lookup itself rest of the
latencies goes to the composition
there's also like 30k uh queries uh per
uh second for the search based timelines
and uh what we have on the input side is
about 340 million tweets a day uh and
growing uh average is
4K Peak is about 6K daily you have large
events can jump up to 10 uh for for for
a little bit now the thing is these
numbers are actually not particularly
impressive on their own you might think
they are they're not we'll get to the
impressive
numbers um so this is
this is a change in a Twitter
traffic over time this is one
day this is the average as you can see
the system is actually running quite a
lot above average which and it on its
own this doesn't really mean anything
but uh but you have to plan for that um
the pattern is closely correlated
obviously with uh when is the sun mostly
up above regions where people tweet a
lot
um however what is interesting is that
when Rafi when Dana tweets or Rafi
tweets they follow each other they will
see each other's tweets but as soon as
you add more people in the mix every
tweet that's tweeted every single one of
those 340 million tweets per day are
delivered to many other people so that's
why it's not so much about 340 million
tweets a day okay whatever but this
means 26 billion deliveries of tweets a
day because each tweet has to be
delivered to many people it's like 18
million per minute you get that down to
I don't know what's what's that in
seconds but it's oh yeah it's it's there
it's 300,000 delivers per second uh it's
a lot that's so many times tweet is
inserted into reddis a tweet is pushed
through a hir cluster a tweet will ring
somebody's
phone that's
300,000 times per second that is an
impressive number and there's an
infrastructure that handles
that so uh the real motivating factor
for why do we want to do this I don't
know how do you see it this
is immediately after following the Japan
earthquake you see the the flow of the
tweets as the earthquake hit as as you
had the global replies and this is why
you need real-time delivery this
is this is what
differentiates data from information
information information is something
that has value for people at the time it
is delivered Twitter delivers
information faster these days days than
anything else on the planet there's this
uh when when that plane landed in Hudson
the New York Times people uh journalists
were watching it from their windows and
they knew they cannot publish it for
several hours until they go to print but
it was on Twitter and uh most recently
well not most recently fortunately it
has been for a while now but the example
that RAF is here had on the
video many of those tweets going in and
out from Japan were tweets about people
giving a sign telling I'm fine and other
people asking are you fine conversation
is also real time and uh and uh and
being able to have a real time two-way
conversation just give give a sign I
mean just think about it the most basic
thing give a sign that you are alive in
the time of trouble now that's a big
thing that's why real-time delivery
matters and with that that's uh all I
had to say thank you
[Applause]